const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Blister cells and bite cells are seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Pyruvate kinase deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions is recombinant erythropoietin indicated for?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia due to malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia due to thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia due to chronic kidney disease","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A patient may present with hemolytic anemia because of genetic mutations in protein synthesis. What is the most common inherited disorder causing anemia in humans in this connection?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Autoimmune hemolytic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What type of anemia is caused by Diphyllobothrium latum (fish tapeworm)?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which of the following conditions will non-neoplastic cells be seen?","answers":[{"option":"Myelodysplastic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple myeloma","bool":false},{"option":"Non-hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of iron deficiency anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Dietary deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Gastrectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Increased demand during puberty","bool":false},{"option":"Malabsorption syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hookworm infestation","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following nail abnormalities is observed in iron deficiency anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Koilonychia","bool":true},{"option":"Pitting","bool":false},{"option":"Splinter hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Erythronychia","bool":false},{"option":"Paronychia","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"For diagnosis of iron deficiency anemia, which one of the following features is seen in the blood film?","answers":[{"option":"Poikilocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Ringed sideroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Target cells","bool":false},{"option":"Bite cells","bool":false},{"option":"Spherocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 9-year-old boy presents to the emergency department with left-sided hemiplegia. There is no history of head trauma to explain this presentation. If he had been diagnosed with anemia a few months ago, which of the following accounts for hemiplegia?","answers":[{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Fainting due to anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple myeloma","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is used to check for the morphology of red blood cells (RBCs)?","answers":[{"option":"Red cell distribution width (RDW)","bool":false},{"option":"Mean corpuscular hemoglobin (MCH)","bool":false},{"option":"Mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (MCHC)","bool":false},{"option":"Mean corpuscular volume (MCV)","bool":true},{"option":"Hematocrit","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Platelet infusion is contraindicated in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (TTP)","bool":true},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)","bool":false},{"option":"Ocular surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the term used for the origin and synthesis of white blood cells (WBCs)?","answers":[{"option":"Hematopoiesis","bool":false},{"option":"Erythropoiesis","bool":false},{"option":"Granulocytopoiesis","bool":false},{"option":"Leukopoiesis","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombopoiesis","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which one of the following conditions are Reed-Sternberg cells seen?","answers":[{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Mantle cell lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Non-Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the diagnostic test for Rh incompatibility?","answers":[{"option":"Chorionic villus sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect Coombs test","bool":true},{"option":"Amniocentesis","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal middle cerebral arterial (MCA) doppler","bool":false},{"option":"Direct Coombs test","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the advantage of fingerprinting?","answers":[{"option":"It does not require any special and expensive instruments","bool":false},{"option":"It is applicable for all people","bool":false},{"option":"It is applicable for all age groups","bool":false},{"option":"It enables absolute identification of an individual","bool":true},{"option":"No special training required","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following are long-lived phagocytic cells present abundantly in gastric tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Dendritic cells","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following cells will be increased in a parasitic reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":true},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the single best test to confirm iron deficiency anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Total iron-binding capacity (TIBC)","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma iron level","bool":false},{"option":"Transferrin saturation","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma ferritin levels","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following cells is dominant in viral infection?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following patient factors is not important to note before a transfusion?","answers":[{"option":"Occupation","bool":true},{"option":"Date of birth","bool":false},{"option":"RhD group","bool":false},{"option":"Sex","bool":false},{"option":"Surname","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which vaccines should be given at birth according to the expanded program on immunization (EPI) schedule?","answers":[{"option":"BCG","bool":false},{"option":"OPV-0","bool":false},{"option":"BCG + OPV-I","bool":false},{"option":"BCG + OPV-0 + Rotavirus-I","bool":false},{"option":"BCG + OPV-0 + hep B","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following represents hot and cold antibodies respectively?","answers":[{"option":"IgD and IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgG and IgM","bool":true},{"option":"IgG and IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgM and IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgA and IgE","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Bernard-Soulier is an inherited disease having giant, non-functional platelets with thrombocytopenia. What is the inheritance pattern of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":true},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 5-year-old child is brought to the emergency department with extreme pain in his hands and feet. Examination reveals dactylitis (swelling of bones), pulmonary infiltrates, and signs and symptoms of anemia. While giving history, the child's parents talk about an inherited disorder that runs in the family. Which condition is the child most likely to be suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP)","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell disease","bool":true},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (TTP)","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is true about aplastic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Hypercellular bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Patients do not require blood support","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatosplenomegaly is not present","bool":true},{"option":"It is not immune mediated","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following constituents is present in hemoglobin A (HbA)?","answers":[{"option":"2 zeta and 2 epsilon chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha and 2 gamma chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha and 2 delta chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 delta and 2 gamma chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha and 2 beta chains","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is correct about mixed cellularity lymphoma?","answers":[{"option":"Does not involve abdominal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Reed-Sternberg cells are not present","bool":false},{"option":"High eosinophils count","bool":true},{"option":"Poor prognosis","bool":false},{"option":"Not caused by Epstein-Barr virus","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 24-year-old man is brought to the emergency after a motorcycle accident. He is bleeding profusely from the wound on his leg. He has no previous medical or surgical history. When a blood smear is performed, what type of red blood cells are likely to be seen?","answers":[{"option":"Macrocytic hypochromic","bool":false},{"option":"Normocytic hypochromic","bool":false},{"option":"Normocytic normochromic","bool":true},{"option":"Microcytic hypochromic","bool":false},{"option":"Macrocytic hypochromic","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is the most common type of Hodgkin lymphoma?","answers":[{"option":"Nodular lymphocyte predominant","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte rich","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte depleted","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed cellularity","bool":false},{"option":"Nodular sclerosis","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 10-year-old child is brought to the hospital with complaints of bloody diarrhea for the past 3 days. Examination and labs reveal an acute kidney injury along with thrombocytopenia. Upon taking history, the parents said that their child had an E. coli infection for the past few days. Which one of the following cells is most likely to be seen in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Bite cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schistocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Tear drop cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cells","bool":false},{"option":"Heinz bodies","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 7-year-old African kid is brought to the clinic with a swelling around his jaw that has been slowly increasing in size over the past few months. Biopsy of the mass reveals a starry sky appearance. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Mantle cell lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following statements is true for Hodgkin's lymphoma?","answers":[{"option":"Lacunar cells are not present","bool":false},{"option":"CD-15 and CD-30 markers are present","bool":true},{"option":"Absence of Reed Sternberg cells","bool":false},{"option":"No eosinophilia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following conditions is most likely to show positive Coomb's test?","answers":[{"option":"Hodgkins lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune hemolytic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 32-year-old female had to undergo a total gastrectomy. After almost 2 years, she started developing weakness, shortness of breath, occasional dizziness and difficulty in walking. She went to her doctor to get a check-up done. On examining her, the doctor noticed that she also had pale skin and yellowing of sclera. What would be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Normocytic normochromic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Microcytic hypochromic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which pattern of serum protein electrophoresis is seen in multiple myeloma?","answers":[{"option":"Monoclonal band","bool":true},{"option":"Double peak","bool":false},{"option":"Polyclonal band","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse band","bool":false},{"option":"Slumped band","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following chromosomal translocations is found in chronic myelogenous leukemia?","answers":[{"option":"t(9;22)","bool":true},{"option":"t(4;14)","bool":false},{"option":"t(8;21)","bool":false},{"option":"t(15;17)","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 12q","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the term used for abnormal and uncontrolled production of white blood cells (WBCs)?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Leukopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Leukopoiesis","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphopenia","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which component of blood is best for transfusion in case of multiple coagulation factor deficiencies?","answers":[{"option":"Cryoprecipitate","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":true},{"option":"Packed red cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pooled platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Whole blood","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is used as an antidote for heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Protamine sulfate","bool":true},{"option":"Succimer","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma (FFP)","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most abundant cell type in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Granulocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Intravascular hemolysis is one of the causes of hemolytic anemia. Which one of the following is not a feature of intravascular hemolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Raised haptoglobin","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hemosiderinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Urobilinogen in urine","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobinemia","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following blood cells have phagocytic activity?","answers":[{"option":"Megakaryocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is most likely seen due to platelet disorders?","answers":[{"option":"Normal platelet count with raised PT and aPTT","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia with normal PT and aPTT","bool":true},{"option":"Normal platelet count with normal PT and aPTT","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia with raised PT but normal aPTT","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia with raised PT and aPTT","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic feature of hemolytic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Increased neutrophil count","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced plasma haptoglobin level","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased reticulocyte count","bool":true},{"option":"Increased unconjugated bilirubin","bool":false},{"option":"Excess urinary urobilinogen","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of tacrolimus?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of inosine monophosphate dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of calcineurin","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of purine synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Destruction of T-cells","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of IL-2 action","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 30-year-old lady received 6 units of blood and developed carpopedal spasm and twitching in her hands, along with flushing of the face. What can be given to relieve her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous 5% dextrose","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous calcium gluconate","bool":true},{"option":"Intravenous water","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous diazepam","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"The diagnosis of Hodgkin lymphoma depends on what histologic finding?","answers":[{"option":"Infiltrative eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Sezary cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pautrier microabscesses","bool":false},{"option":"Auer rods","bool":false},{"option":"Reed-Sternberg cells","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which coagulation factor is deficient in hemophilia B?","answers":[{"option":"IX","bool":true},{"option":"V","bool":false},{"option":"XI","bool":false},{"option":"II","bool":false},{"option":"VIII","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which vitamin deficiency can lead to a protein C deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following types of immunity occurs when an individual is administered with an immunoglobulin made in another host?","answers":[{"option":"Artificial","bool":false},{"option":"Active","bool":false},{"option":"Innate","bool":false},{"option":"Natural","bool":false},{"option":"Passive","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following conversions uses vitamin B12 as a co-factor?","answers":[{"option":"Serine to glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Succinyl CoA to succinate","bool":false},{"option":"Homocysteine to methionine","bool":true},{"option":"Pyruvate to acetyl coA","bool":false},{"option":"Oxaloacetate to citrate","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions is true about the leukemoid reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Response to an infection","bool":true},{"option":"Blood smear contains mature white blood cells and red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Only involves neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Always presents with abnormal bone marrow","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the movement of white blood cells in to the tissues in response to interleukins called?","answers":[{"option":"Clumping","bool":false},{"option":"Precipitation","bool":false},{"option":"Proliferation of lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Diapedesis","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotaxis","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What type of vaccine is the diphtheria vaccine?","answers":[{"option":"Immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Toxin","bool":false},{"option":"Live attenuated","bool":false},{"option":"Toxoid","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"The erythropoietin receptor belongs to which class of receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine kinase receptor","bool":false},{"option":"G protein-coupled receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Ligand-gated ion channel","bool":false},{"option":"Intracellular receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Cytokine receptor","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase (TdT) is a marker for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mature B and T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Reed-Sternberg cells","bool":false},{"option":"NK cells and granulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Germinal centre B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-B and pre-T cells","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In sickle cell anemia, glutamate at the 6th position of the beta chain of hemoglobin is substituted by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Valine","bool":true},{"option":"Proline","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Lysine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following agents is a potent iron chelator?","answers":[{"option":"Ferrous sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Unithiol","bool":false},{"option":"Succimer","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrous gluconate","bool":false},{"option":"Deferoxamine","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 24-year-old presents with bruises in the emergency department. Laboratory results showed normal bleeding time but prolonged prothrombin time (PT) and partial thromboplastin time (PTT). Which one of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"von Willebrand factor (VWF)","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation disorder","bool":true},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (TTP)","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following antibodies of the recipient is responsible for causing urticaria in the donor's blood?","answers":[{"option":"Ig G antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Ig A antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Ig D antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Ig M antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Ig E antibodies","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 35-year-old man with a history of intravenous (IV) drug abuse has generalized lymphadenopathy. Which of the following tests would help in finding the cause of his lymphadenopathy?","answers":[{"option":"HIV serology","bool":true},{"option":"Bone marrow biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Histopathology","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasonography","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC)","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 37-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of a lump in the right breast. The general physical examination concludes mass in the right upper quadrant of the breast and an enlarged right axial lymph node. She was diagnosed with Hodgkin lymphoma 7 years ago but was treated for it and completely cured. What is the most likely diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Fibroadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myeloid leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Breast cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Non-Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the most common gene mutation in alpha thalassemia?","answers":[{"option":"Nonsense mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Missense mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Splice mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Gene deletion","bool":true},{"option":"Frameshift mutation","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is immunization to the whole community referred to as?","answers":[{"option":"Innate immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Herd immunity","bool":true},{"option":"Active immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Adaptive immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Passive immunity","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Stunted and notched upper central incisors are most likely to be found in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Scurvy","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital syphilis","bool":true},{"option":"Fetal alcohol syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Plummer vinson syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following are non-neoplastic cells?","answers":[{"option":"Blast cells","bool":true},{"option":"Popcorn cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mononuclear cells","bool":false},{"option":"Lacunar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Reed Steerberg cells","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is implicated in Hodgkin's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Thymus","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Blood","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A girl presented to the emergency with a complaint of easy bruising and petechia, which is on and off. Her brother also suffered from the same condition. The lab results of the girl showed increased bleeding and partial thromboplastin time. Which one of the following conditions was she suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":true},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A female presented with gingival bleeding, fever, and headache to the outpatient department (OPD). Her lab results showed normal partial thromboplastin time (PTT) and prothrombin time (PT) but increased bleeding time. Her blood smear showed the presence of schistocytes. Which one is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":true},{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which surgery most commonly causes deep vein thrombosis (DVT)?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiothoracic surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG)","bool":false},{"option":"Hip surgery","bool":true},{"option":"Carpal tunnel surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the diagnostic test for deep vein thrombosis (DVT)?","answers":[{"option":"D-dimer test","bool":false},{"option":"Doppler ultrasound","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"Venography","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT)","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which drug should be given to a patient with deep vein thrombosis (DVT)?","answers":[{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Coumarin","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":true},{"option":"Alteplase","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 6-year-old child, diagnosed with hereditary spherocytosis, complained of increased frequency of blood transfusions. Blood complete picture shows Hb=6.5 gm/dL, reticulocyte count=20%, TLC=4000/mm³, platelets=100,000/mm³. What will be the most appropriate treatment for this child?","answers":[{"option":"Repeated transfusions with iron chelation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxyurea","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow transplant","bool":false},{"option":"Splenectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroids with antithymhocytic globulin","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 24-year-old boy was brought to the emergency with a petechial hemorrhage with no fever. Upon examination, he had mild splenomegaly but no neurological symptoms. His laboratory results showed prolonged bleeding time but normal prothrombin time (PT) and partial thromboplastin time (PTT). Which one of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP)","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (TTP)","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic-uremic syndrome (HUS)","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A patient presented with disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) due to sepsis by gram-negative bacteria in the emergency. Which one of the following is the first step for the management of DIC in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"IV antibiotic + IV hydration","bool":true},{"option":"Platelet","bool":false},{"option":"Whole blood","bool":false},{"option":"Cryoprecipitate","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is not correct about non-Hodgkin lymphoma?","answers":[{"option":"t(14:18) in follicular lymphoma results in dysregulated BCL2 expression","bool":false},{"option":"Males have a slightly higher risk","bool":false},{"option":"Epstein-Barr virus is associated with post-transplant non-Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Median age is 65-70 years","bool":false},{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma is most aggressive and incurable","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What antibody is found in antiphospholipid syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-cyclic citrullinated peptide (anti-CCP) antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid factor (RF)","bool":false},{"option":"Antinuclear antibody (ANA)","bool":false},{"option":"Anticardiolipin antibody","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-double stranded DNA (Anti-dsDNA) antibody","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of polycythemia?","answers":[{"option":"Headache","bool":false},{"option":"Pruritus","bool":false},{"option":"Cyanosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatosplenomegaly","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A man has a history of eczema and allergic asthma. Which diagnostic test is performed?","answers":[{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cell sedimentation","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral blood smear","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC)","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 4-year-old girl presents with skin pallor for the past 3 days. One week ago she had a history of bloody diarrhea. Examination showed petechiae on the upper limbs. Laboratory studies revealed Hb 7.1 g/dl, reticulocytes 14%, platelets 30x 109/L, and normal WBC count. The renal function is deranged. The peripheral smear features numerous schistocytes and occasional nucleated RBC. Given the findings, which of the following bacteria is involved in the pathophysiology of disease?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella dysenteriae","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Spontaneous bleeding becomes evident when the platelet count falls below which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"20,000 platelets per microliter blood","bool":true},{"option":"40,000 platelets per microliter blood","bool":false},{"option":"100,000 platelets per microliter blood","bool":false},{"option":"60,000 platelets per microliter blood","bool":false},{"option":"75,000 platelets per microliter blood","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A child presents with an enlarged spleen and jaundice. His laboratory findings include an increased red blood cell width, spherocytes with loss of pallor, and increased mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (MCHC). Which of the following would be a possible diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Myeloproliferative disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is most commonly not found among all types of myeloproliferative disorders?","answers":[{"option":"Hypocellular bone marrow","bool":true},{"option":"JAK 2 kinase mutation","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercellular bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Involves myoblasts","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is a cause of neutropenia?","answers":[{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Allergic reaction","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Addison's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true about acute myelogenous leukemia?","answers":[{"option":"Not caused due to alkylating agents or radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Gum infiltration","bool":true},{"option":"No association with Down syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Involves cyclin D1 mutation","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Patients with severe liver disease are most likely to develop which of the following pathological findings?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Patient will be unresponsive to vitamin K injection","bool":true},{"option":"Defect in Gp1B receptors of platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Normal PT and APTT","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bleeding time","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following substances are released from granules in basophils?","answers":[{"option":"Histamine and heparin","bool":true},{"option":"vWF","bool":false},{"option":"ADP and calcium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen and fibronectin","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is observed in chronic myeloid leukemia?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophilia with increased IgE","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cell degranulation","bool":false},{"option":"JAK 2 tyrosine kinase mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Basophilia","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which of the following conditions will eosinophilia be observed?","answers":[{"option":"Septic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Cushing's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Protozoal and parasitic infection","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 65-year-old man presented to the clinic with complaints of severe backache. The doctor ordered laboratory tests that revealed a hemoglobin level of 7.0 mg/dL and serum creatinine of 2.0 mg/dL. Which of the following findings would also be included in the report?","answers":[{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":true},{"option":"Oxaluria","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following hemoglobins are present in thalassemia major?","answers":[{"option":"Normal HbA, increased HbA2 (2-8%)","bool":false},{"option":"Normal HbA, increased HbA2 and more than 90% HbF","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased HbA, raised HbA2 and HbF","bool":false},{"option":"Normal HbA and increased HbF","bool":false},{"option":"HbA absent, HbA2 normal or high or low, HbF markedly increased","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 5-day-old baby born after a healthy, full-term pregnancy started bleeding into his genitals. His mother took anti-epileptic drugs throughout her pregnancy. What is the likely cause of the bleeding disorder in this infant?","answers":[{"option":"Alcohol abuse","bool":false},{"option":"Long-term phenobarbital","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Poisoning","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which one of the following scenarios is vitamin K given?","answers":[{"option":"Peptic ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Worm infection","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive jaundice","bool":true},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Colonic polyp","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is donor blood screened for before a transfusion?","answers":[{"option":"Parasitic infection","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":true},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal infection","bool":false},{"option":"Protozoal infection","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A pregnant woman in her 3rd trimester is diagnosed with iron deficiency anemia. Which of the following type of cells will be found on her blood smear?","answers":[{"option":"Hypochromic, Microcytic","bool":true},{"option":"Hypochromic, Normocytic","bool":false},{"option":"Hypochromic, Normocytic","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperchromic, Normocytic","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperchromic, Macrocytic","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements about Hodgkin lymphoma is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Negative for CD15 and CD30","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed cellularity is the most commonly found Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Painful enlargement of lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of Reed sternberg cells","bool":true}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following lymphomas is involved in the Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) infection?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple myeloma","bool":false},{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Kaposi's sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A child suffering from hemolytic uremic syndrome will have which one of the following finding in his peripheral blood smear?","answers":[{"option":"Schistocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Howell-jolly bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Target cells","bool":false},{"option":"Tear drop RBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Aur rods","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 5-month-old child presented with bleeding from the genitals. His maternal uncle had a history of prolonged bleeding. What will be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":true},{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin induced thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true about tacrolimus?","answers":[{"option":"Stimulates T-cell activation","bool":false},{"option":"Calcineurin inhibitor","bool":true},{"option":"IL-2 transcription occurs","bool":false},{"option":"Does not bind to FK506 protein","bool":false},{"option":"Does not cause nephrotoxicity","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Why is low molecular weight heparin (LMWH) preferred over unfractionated heparin (UFH)?","answers":[{"option":"LMWH can be taken orally","bool":false},{"option":"LMWH can be given in all conditions","bool":false},{"option":"LMWH has no side effects","bool":false},{"option":"LMWH has longer half life","bool":true},{"option":"LMWH has lesser half life","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which one of the following blue granules are most likely to be seen?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":true},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following cells is present in acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"T lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of vitamin B12 deficiency anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Diphyllobothrium","bool":false},{"option":"Veganism","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrointestinal TB","bool":false},{"option":"Ileal resection","bool":false},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the first immediate sign after death?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Putrefaction","bool":false},{"option":"Rigor mortis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary relaxation","bool":true},{"option":"Stiffening","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A guy who shoots himself tends to get instantaneous rigor instead of rigor mortis. Which one of the following statements most likely signifies the difference between the two?","answers":[{"option":"Instantaneous rigor indicates time of death instead of mode of death","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle contraction is less marked in instantaneous rigor mortis","bool":false},{"option":"Instantaneous rigor mortis is not immediate after the death","bool":false},{"option":"Instantaneous rigor affects all the muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Primary relaxation is absent in instantaneous rigor mortis","bool":true}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A dead body is found by a group of people near the station. It is concluded that 6 to 10 hours have passed since the time of death. Which one of the following is most likely to be developed by this time in the body?","answers":[{"option":"Instantaneous rigor","bool":false},{"option":"Postmortem caloricity","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium increase in CSF","bool":false},{"option":"Rigor mortis","bool":false},{"option":"Postmortem lividity","bool":true}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 52-year-old patient presented to the clinic to get his blood reports examined. He was being investigated following his presentation to the clinic with a history of recurrent infections and easy fatiguability for 6 months. The peripheral film demonstrated peculiar monocytes twice the size of mature lymphocytes with round nuclei, abundant cytoplasm, and circumferential projections. An attempt to perform bone marrow aspiration revealed a dry tap. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Acute myeloid leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Infectious mononucleosis","bool":false},{"option":"Prolymphocytic leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following factors promotes sickling?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial illness","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotonicity","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydration","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which condition shows both arterial and venous thrombosis?","answers":[{"option":"Factor V Leiden mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Protein S deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Antithrombin deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Protein C deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Antiphospholipid antibody syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A patient presents with chipmunk-like facies and a crew-cut appearance of the skull on X-ray. Laboratory investigations show increased fetal hemoglobin (HbF). What is the most likely underlying cause?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-thalassemia minor","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-thalassemia major","bool":true},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 22-year-old woman attends an antenatal booking appointment. She has had previous 3 miscarriages. She has mouth ulcers and joint pains and is evaluated for arthritis/ arthralgia. Which single pair of results are most likely to confirm the underlying cause of her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased hemoglobin and decreased mean corpuscular volume (MCV)","bool":false},{"option":"Increased activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) and decreased platelets","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease hemoglobin and increased reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Increased erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) and rheumatoid factor","bool":false},{"option":"Increased lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) and increased bilirubin","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A child suffering from beta-thalassemia is most likely to present the clinical features at the age of:","answers":[{"option":"10 to 12 months after birth","bool":false},{"option":"few months before the birth","bool":false},{"option":"6 to 9 months after birth","bool":true},{"option":"In middle age","bool":false},{"option":"1 year after birth","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following gene products is seen in chronic myelogenous leukemia?","answers":[{"option":"BCL-2","bool":false},{"option":"Heavy chain Ig and BCL-2","bool":false},{"option":"BCR-ABL","bool":true},{"option":"Heavy chain Ig and c-myc","bool":false},{"option":"c-myc","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following diseases is associated with platelet aggregation defect?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic-uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Bernard-Soulier syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following blood tests is done to detect sickle cell disease?","answers":[{"option":"flow cytometry","bool":false},{"option":"Serum protein electrophoresis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin electrophoresis","bool":true},{"option":"Schilling test","bool":false},{"option":"Osmotic fragility test","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A person exposed to asbestos is more likely to develop which type of cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Oropharyngeal carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Breast cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural solitary fibrous tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":true}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs does NOT work by inhibiting ADP binding to platelet receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Abciximab","bool":true},{"option":"Prasugrel","bool":false},{"option":"Ticagrelor","bool":false},{"option":"Ticlopidine","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits only factor Xa?","answers":[{"option":"Rivaroxiban","bool":true},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Unfractionated Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Bivalirudin","bool":false},{"option":"Argatroban","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which of the following conditions is streptokinase contraindicated?","answers":[{"option":"DIC","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Acute MI","bool":false},{"option":"DVT","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is a platelet aggregating inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Argatroban","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":true},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Dabigatran","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements best describe compliance with a drug?","answers":[{"option":"Doctors and patients needs are fully articulated","bool":true},{"option":"By telling its side effects","bool":false},{"option":"By telling its outcomes","bool":false},{"option":"Give details about the alternative treatments","bool":false},{"option":"By telling the diagnosis to the patient","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following set of people are most vulnerable to indoor air pollution?","answers":[{"option":"Middle aged men","bool":false},{"option":"Elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Any aged person","bool":false},{"option":"Women and children","bool":true},{"option":"Pregnant women","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Through which of the following bones age and sex determination of a skeleton can be determined?","answers":[{"option":"Ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Radius and ulna","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Skull and mandible","bool":true},{"option":"Metacarpals","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Stage IV of Hodgkin lymphoma has a prognosis of:","answers":[{"option":"60 to 70 %","bool":true},{"option":"10 to 15 %","bool":false},{"option":"70 to 90 %","bool":false},{"option":"20 to 40 %","bool":false},{"option":"0 to 10 %","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is diapedesis?","answers":[{"option":"Attachment of leukocytes to endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Movement of leukocytes into the tissues","bool":false},{"option":"Recruitment of leukocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Migration of leukocytes through the endothelium","bool":true},{"option":"Leukocytes aggregation","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following tumors is the neoplasm of T helper cells?","answers":[{"option":"Mantle cell lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal zone lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Sézary syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":127,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which of the following condition mean corpuscular volume (MCV) is low?","answers":[{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Folate deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Vitamin K deficiency leads to:","answers":[{"option":"Increased bleeding time","bool":false},{"option":"Increased PT and PTT","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased platelet count","bool":false},{"option":"Increased PT","bool":false},{"option":"Increased PTT","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following describes the mode of transmission of hemophilia A?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":true},{"option":"X- linked dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial disease","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the best test for disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)?","answers":[{"option":"Increased fibrinogen concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased PT and PTT","bool":false},{"option":"D-dimer","bool":true},{"option":"International normalized ratio (INR)","bool":false},{"option":"Increased coagulation factors","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Low erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) represents:","answers":[{"option":"Increased hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Increased red blood cell count","bool":false},{"option":"Increased hematocrit","bool":false},{"option":"No rouleaux formation","bool":true},{"option":"Rouleaux formation","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Heinz bodies in erythrocytes are characteristic features of:","answers":[{"option":"Glutathione reductase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Glutathione peroxidase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"G6PD deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Glucokinase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Pyruvate kinase deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions causes the anemia that occurs due to a defect in RBCs' membrane protein?","answers":[{"option":"Warm immunohemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Sickle cell disease","bool":false},{"option":"Paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Paroxysmal cold hemoglobinuria","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following antibodies would be present in a person having blood group B?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Anti Rh antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"IgM and IgG antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti B antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti A antibodies","bool":true}]},{"id":135,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the side effect of warfarin?","answers":[{"option":"Ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac toxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Myelosuppression","bool":false},{"option":"Severe birth defects","bool":true}]},{"id":136,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is not a baseline investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Lipid profile","bool":false},{"option":"Urine DR","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar puncture","bool":true},{"option":"HbA1c","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 5-year-old presents in an outpatient department with a history of fatigue, headache, and dyspnea. On examination, he was found to be having pale conjunctiva. Upon inquiring her mother she reported that she lost her previous child due to hydrops fetalis. Which thalassemia is incompatible with hydrops fetalis?","answers":[{"option":"Mild Alpha thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Severe Alpha thalassemia","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Minor Beta thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Major Beta thalassemia","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Macrocytic cells are the most common findings in megaloblastic anemia. Which of the following statements best describe about its cause?","answers":[{"option":"Folate deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B6 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12 and folate deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Iron deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements describe leukoerythroblastosis?","answers":[{"option":"Immature red blood cells and white blood cells","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Mature red blood cells and white blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Increased reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Megakaryocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following condition has microcytic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":true},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"If a blood smear is taken from a patient having leukoerythroblstosis. What will be the laboratory findings?","answers":[{"option":"Mature white blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Anucleate red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Immature red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Immature red blood cells and white blood cells","bool":true}]},{"id":142,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Howell-jolly bodies are seen in:","answers":[{"option":"G6PD deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Liver disease","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Post splenectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Myelodysplastic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A baby undergoes circumcision and after the procedure the bleeding is prolonged. Upon inquiry, his brothers and sisters have had the same problem. What test should be done for the assessment?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombin time","bool":false},{"option":"Acute partial thromboplastin time","bool":true},{"option":"Prothrombin time","bool":false},{"option":"Platelet count","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding time","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What will be the risk of inheritance of X-linked disease in the male child if the mother is a carrier and the father is genotypically normal?","answers":[{"option":"25%","bool":false},{"option":"75%","bool":false},{"option":"0%","bool":false},{"option":"50%","bool":true},{"option":"100%","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"The extrinsic pathway of coagulation is initiated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Complement system","bool":false},{"option":"Antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue thromboplastin factor","bool":true},{"option":"Vasoconstriction of venules","bool":false},{"option":"Subendothelial collagen","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of disseminated intravascular coagulation?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial sepsis","bool":true},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypovolemic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Massive trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pancreatitis","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following drug causes cardiac toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Dactinomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Bleomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Doxorubicin","bool":true},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false}]},{"id":148,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Hemoglobinuria is a feature of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Intravascular hemolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Extravascular hemolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":149,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Monocytosis is seen in which of the following situations?","answers":[{"option":"Acute myeloid leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Polycythemia vera","bool":false},{"option":"Wilsons disease","bool":false}]},{"id":150,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the feature of chronic hemolytic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of ferritin","bool":false},{"option":"Increased transferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Hemosiderinuria","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of iron","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobinemia","bool":false}]},{"id":151,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is given to a patient suffering from hemophilia A?","answers":[{"option":"Recombinant factor 8","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroid's","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmapheresis","bool":false}]},{"id":152,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following substances are required for effective iron absorption?","answers":[{"option":"Folic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Zinc","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false}]},{"id":153,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statement is not true about acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL)?","answers":[{"option":"B-ALL is more common than T-ALL","bool":false},{"option":"Can be B-ALL or T-ALL","bool":false},{"option":"Most common cancer of children","bool":false},{"option":"No blast cell seen in both marrow and periphery","bool":true},{"option":"Has >20% blast cells","bool":false}]},{"id":154,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is the feature of aplastic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Reticulocytopenia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypercellular bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased myeloid cells","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":false}]},{"id":155,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 10-year-old child who is otherwise healthy got a complete blood count done which showed Hb of 10 gm/dL, with hypochromic and microcytic red cell indices. Her pediatrician is assuming her to be a carrier of the beta-thalassemia trait. Which of the following tests will confirm her diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Schilling test","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin electrophoresis","bool":true},{"option":"Osmotic fragility test","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":156,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following antibodies are present in Bernard-Soulier syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Glycoprotein Ib antibodies","bool":true},{"option":"Glycoprotein IIa/IIIb antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Glycoprotein Ib/IIIb antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Platelet membrane phospholipids","bool":false},{"option":"Glycoprotein IIa","bool":false}]},{"id":157,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is not used in the treatment of iron deficiency anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Ferrous gluconate","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Ferrous fumarate","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonyl iron","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrous sulfate","bool":false}]},{"id":158,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"When is brain death declared?","answers":[{"option":"When there is no pulse","bool":false},{"option":"When person stops breathing","bool":false},{"option":"When there is no proper circulation","bool":false},{"option":"When there is loss of brainstem reflexes","bool":true},{"option":"When there is no oxygen delivery","bool":false}]},{"id":159,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following results in sickle cell crisis?","answers":[{"option":"Vaso-occlusive crisis","bool":true},{"option":"Sickling","bool":false},{"option":"Autosplenectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic crisis","bool":false},{"option":"Sequestration crisis","bool":false}]},{"id":160,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most feared complication in sickle cell disease?","answers":[{"option":"Auto-splenectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Sequestration crisis","bool":false},{"option":"Dactylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute chest syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":161,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following term is used for skin bleeding, which is greater than 3 mm but less than 1 cm?","answers":[{"option":"Purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Hemarthrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Epistaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Ecchymoses","bool":false},{"option":"Petechiae","bool":false}]},{"id":162,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following are indications of death?","answers":[{"option":"Normal electrocardiogram (ECG)","bool":false},{"option":"Normal electroencephalogram (EEG)","bool":false},{"option":"Stop breathing after an hour","bool":false},{"option":"Flat electroencephalogram (EEG), flat electrocardiogram (ECG), stop breathing within 5 minutes","bool":true},{"option":"Weak pulse","bool":false}]},{"id":163,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of death in sickle cell disease?","answers":[{"option":"Auto-splenectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic crisis","bool":false},{"option":"Dactylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute Chest Syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Sequestration crisis","bool":false}]},{"id":164,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A middle-aged man presents with excessive bleeding after a minor cut in the OPD. On examination, his lab results showed increased bleeding time but normal prothrombin time (PT) and partial thromboplastin time (PTT). His lab work also showed increased megakaryocytes with no other abnormality in other myeloid lineages. Which of the following condition is most likely present in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":true},{"option":"Leukopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":false}]},{"id":165,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statement represents asphyxial death?","answers":[{"option":"Petechiae and congestion","bool":false},{"option":"Bluish face, congested conjunctiva, and petechial hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Cyanosis only","bool":false},{"option":"Petechiae only","bool":false},{"option":"No petechiae","bool":false}]},{"id":166,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statement represents mean corpuscular hemoglobin (MCH)?","answers":[{"option":"Average mass of WBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Average mass of hemoglobin in one RBC","bool":true},{"option":"Average volume of one RBC","bool":false},{"option":"Average mass of hemoglobin in RBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Average volume of RBCs","bool":false}]},{"id":167,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which situation the claim of abortion can be false?","answers":[{"option":"Menopausal stage","bool":true},{"option":"Multiparous woman","bool":false},{"option":"Girl in her puberty stage","bool":false},{"option":"Women in her mid 30s","bool":false},{"option":"Woman who just crossed her 20s","bool":false}]},{"id":168,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a platelet inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Abciximab","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":true},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Ticlopidine","bool":false}]},{"id":169,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Anti-malarial drugs cause hemolysis in which of the following disease?","answers":[{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Myelodysplastic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphocytic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency","bool":true}]},{"id":170,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 50-year-old man came to an outpatient department with the complaint of having a rash immediately after taking a shower. Which of the following describes his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple myeloma","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia Vera","bool":true},{"option":"Gaisbocks syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":171,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Henoch-Schonlein purpura is caused by systemic deposition of:","answers":[{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Immune complexes","bool":true},{"option":"Epitheloid cells","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":172,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following does not happen in platelet disorders?","answers":[{"option":"Ecchymoses","bool":false},{"option":"Petechiae","bool":false},{"option":"Hemarthrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Mucosal bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false}]},{"id":173,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Myelodysplastic syndrome is NOT characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ineffective lymphopoiesis","bool":true},{"option":"Heterogenous clonal stem cell disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs in elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Ineffective hematopoiesis","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia, neutropenia and thrombocytopenia","bool":false}]},{"id":174,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"In which of the following condition, alteplase is given?","answers":[{"option":"Prevention of stroke","bool":false},{"option":"Normal bleeding and coagulation time","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary stenting","bool":false},{"option":"Acute ischemic stroke","bool":true},{"option":"Vasodilation","bool":false}]},{"id":175,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A cord blood sample of an Rh-ve mother was sent for laboratory testing during labor. Which of the following would indicate the need for blood exchange transfusion?","answers":[{"option":"Reticulocyte is corrected to 7%","bool":true},{"option":"Hemoglobin = 10 mg/dL","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect coombs test is weakly negative","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral cells shows spherocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Serum bilirubin = 2.5 mg/dL","bool":false}]},{"id":176,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following factors does NOT  promote the sickling of red blood cells?","answers":[{"option":"Obesity","bool":true},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydration","bool":false}]},{"id":177,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is not classified as a platelet functional disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Bernard soulier syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthemia","bool":false},{"option":"Grey platelet syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenia purpura","bool":true}]},{"id":178,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"How is alteplase formed?","answers":[{"option":"Made by bacteria in the colon","bool":false},{"option":"Derived from animal sources","bool":false},{"option":"It is naturally found","bool":false},{"option":"Recombinant DNA technology","bool":true},{"option":"Dervied from plant sources","bool":false}]},{"id":179,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Increased homocysteine levels result in?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Osteonecrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Atherosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false}]},{"id":180,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 14-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with a complaint of weakness and fever for the past few weeks. On examination, there was increased leukocyte count with normal red blood cell and platelet count. His chest CT further showed a mediastinal mass. Which of the following is the most likely condition from which the boy is suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic myelogenous leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myelogenous leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":181,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true about heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Doesn't binds to antithrombin III","bool":false},{"option":"Antidote is vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Is antiplatelet drug","bool":false},{"option":"Teratogenic","bool":false},{"option":"Can be given in pregnancy","bool":true}]},{"id":182,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common clinical manifestation in Von Willebrand's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Gum bleeding","bool":true},{"option":"Joint bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Deep tissue bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Rectal bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Post surgical bleeding","bool":false}]},{"id":183,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"The triad of symptoms, thrombocytopenia, acute kidney injury and microangiopathic hemolytic anemia, is seen in which of the following condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic-uremic syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":false},{"option":"Bernard-Soulier syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false}]},{"id":184,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding cyclophosphamide?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibitor of hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Alkylating agent","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrimidine analog","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibitor of dihydrofolate reductase","bool":false},{"option":"IL-2 inhibitor","bool":false}]},{"id":185,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true about fibrinolytics?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"They cause allergy and antibody production","bool":true},{"option":"Urokinase directly inhibits plasminogen","bool":false},{"option":"Streptokinase directly inhibits plasminogen","bool":false},{"option":"Contraindicated in acute myocardial infarction","bool":false}]},{"id":186,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following condition presents with the usage of platelets and the coagulation factors, along with microangiopathic hemolytic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Bernard-Soulier syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":false},{"option":"hemolytic-uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":true}]},{"id":187,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 20-year-old man whose femur got fractured in a road traffic accident is bleeding profusely from the fracture site. What should he be transfused with?","answers":[{"option":"Packed red cell concentrate","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Whole blood","bool":true},{"option":"Cryoprecipitate","bool":false},{"option":"Pooled platelets","bool":false}]},{"id":188,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 20-year-old man is brought into the emergency after a road traffic accident. As a result, he is suspected to be infected by tetanus. Which of the following vaccine will be given to this man?","answers":[{"option":"Live attenuated","bool":false},{"option":"Toxoid and immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Toxoid","bool":true},{"option":"Dead virus","bool":false}]},{"id":189,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following best describes the function of interleukins?","answers":[{"option":"To prevent mucosal bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Rolling of white blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Vasodilation of arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Diapedesis","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotaxis","bool":true}]},{"id":190,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following would the 2nd line treatment for a patient suffering from sickle cell anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"IV vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmapheresis","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxyurea","bool":true},{"option":"Desmopressin","bool":false}]},{"id":191,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Extramedullary hematopoiesis occurs due to myelodysplastic fibrosis. Which of the following would be the most common site of extramedullary hematopoiesis?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":true},{"option":"Thymus","bool":false},{"option":"Bones","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid","bool":false}]},{"id":192,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Spherocytosis is seen in which other conditions than hereditary spherocytosis?","answers":[{"option":"Infection-induced hemolytic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Autosplenectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":193,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 40-year-old man undergoes successful surgery. On the second postoperative day, he developed a high-grade fever. It was later found out that the doctors had inadvertently left a swab in his abdomen. Which type of negligence is this?","answers":[{"option":"Civil negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Res-Ipsa-Loquotar","bool":false},{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":true}]},{"id":194,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 50-year-old man visits a medical center with complaints of dyspnea and fatigue. On examination, he was found to have generalized lymphadenopathy and jaundice. His blood smear showed smudge cells. Which of the following is a complication if a patient suffering is from Chronic lymphocytic leukemia?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune hemolytic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Fever, rash and itchy back","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatosplenomegaly","bool":false}]},{"id":195,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"The administration of a private hospital does not provide quality instruments to the doctors. Which type of negligence is this?","answers":[{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate negligence","bool":true},{"option":"Res ipsa loquitur","bool":false},{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Civil negligence","bool":false}]},{"id":196,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the World Health Organization's criteria for anemia in infants?","answers":[{"option":"Hb < 11.0 gm/dL","bool":true},{"option":"Hb < 14.0 gm/dL","bool":false},{"option":"Hb < 12.0 gm/dL","bool":false},{"option":"Hb < 10.0 gm/dL","bool":false},{"option":"Hb < 13.5 gm/dL","bool":false}]},{"id":197,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"How much hemoglobin and hematocrit are increased respectively when one pint of blood is transfused?","answers":[{"option":"3 mg/dl and 1 %","bool":false},{"option":"0 mg/dl and 2 %","bool":false},{"option":"2 mg/dl and 0 %","bool":false},{"option":"5 mg/dl and 10 %","bool":false},{"option":"1 mg/dl and 3 %","bool":true}]},{"id":198,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Ringed sideroblasts are seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Myelodysplastic syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":199,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"The lacunar variant of Reed-Sternberg (RS) cells is found in:","answers":[{"option":"Mixed cellularity","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte rich","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte depletion","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte predominant","bool":false},{"option":"Nodular sclerosis","bool":true}]},{"id":200,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 14-year-old boy presents to the outpatient department (OPD) with weakness and fever. On examination, his bone marrow showed 80% hypercellularity but 3% myeloblasts. Which of the following condition is most likely associated with his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Acute myelogenous leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic myelogenous leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":201,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A man presents to the emergency with weakness. On examination, Reed-Sternberg cells were found along with swelling of a lymph node. There were no systemic symptoms reported. The doctor concluded his condition as Hodgkin lymphoma. What is the stage of lymphoma in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Stage IB","bool":false},{"option":"Stage IV","bool":false},{"option":"Stage II","bool":false},{"option":"Stage IA","bool":true},{"option":"Stage III","bool":false}]},{"id":202,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"How is acute leukemia differentiated by chronic leukemia?","answers":[{"option":"Presence of blast cells","bool":true},{"option":"Aggressive nature","bool":false},{"option":"Size","bool":false},{"option":"Metastasis","bool":false},{"option":"Location","bool":false}]},{"id":203,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following Gustafson's method is most reliable?","answers":[{"option":"Cement apposition","bool":false},{"option":"Loosening of teeth","bool":false},{"option":"Root transparency","bool":true},{"option":"Root resorption","bool":false},{"option":"Gradual wearing out of teeth","bool":false}]},{"id":204,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Auer rods in the cytoplasm are a classical finding of which of the following neoplasms?","answers":[{"option":"Hodgkin Lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic myelogenous leukemia (CML)","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL)","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL)","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myeloid leukemia (AML)","bool":true}]},{"id":205,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of these is not prepared from human blood?","answers":[{"option":"Cryoprecipitate","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Packed cells","bool":false},{"option":"Recombinant factor VIII","bool":true}]},{"id":206,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A patient having B-Thalassemia on regular transfusions starts to develop urticaria in the past 4 to 5 months. Which of the following should be given to him before his next transfusion session?","answers":[{"option":"Antihistamines","bool":true},{"option":"Anti Rh negative antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Antimalarial","bool":false},{"option":"Washed blood","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false}]},{"id":207,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the daily requirement of iron in pregnant females?","answers":[{"option":"14.7 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"0.4 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"2 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"7 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"3.4 mg/dl","bool":true}]},{"id":208,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A body is found in the jungle resisting to blanch on pressure. How many hours have elapsed after the death of this person?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"1 to 3 hours","bool":false},{"option":"24 hours","bool":false},{"option":"10 to 12 hours","bool":true},{"option":"5 to 6 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":209,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Koilonychia is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":false},{"option":"Neutropenia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":210,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is used as a corrosive used for cleaning rust?","answers":[{"option":"Aluminum","bool":false},{"option":"Oxalic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrogen peroxide","bool":false},{"option":"Zinc oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Copper","bool":false}]},{"id":211,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Heparin works in association with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Calmodulin","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Dense proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Antithrombin III","bool":true}]},{"id":212,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following statements best describes neoadjuvant chemotherapy?","answers":[{"option":"Chemotherapy given during surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotherapy given as a supplemental treatment after surgery or radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotherapy given in low doses to prolong remission","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotherapy given as a supplemental treatment during radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotherapy given prior to surgery in an attempt to shrink the tumor","bool":true}]},{"id":213,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is NOT the most common complication of chemotherapy?","answers":[{"option":"Vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Alopecia","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Stomatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Myelosuppression","bool":false}]},{"id":214,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"The postmortem sign of 'cattle trucking' is seen in which organ?","answers":[{"option":"Cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Retina","bool":true},{"option":"Limbs","bool":false}]},{"id":215,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is associated with thalassemia disease?","answers":[{"option":"Defective globin chains","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Deficient globin chains","bool":true}]},{"id":216,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A man presents to the emergency with tenderness on his left upper quadrant and yellow discoloration of the skin.  On examination, he is found to have icterus and splenomegaly. His lab results show increased total bilirubin levels but normal direct bilirubin. His blood smear further show an increased number of reticulocytes. Which of the following is the most likely reason for this?","answers":[{"option":"Thromocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":217,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A baby is born to a full-term mother through vaginal delivery. He has tortuous and dilated veins that are widely distributed on his skin and mucous membranes. Which of the following is the most likely condition that the baby is suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Sickle cell disease","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP)","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary hemorrhagic telangiectasia","bool":true},{"option":"Varicose veins","bool":false}]},{"id":218,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the diagnostic test for Hodgkin lymphoma?","answers":[{"option":"The site of lymph node involved","bool":false},{"option":"Fine Needle Aspiration Cytology (FNAC)","bool":false},{"option":"Checking tenderness of the lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Excision biopsy with histopathology","bool":true},{"option":"Biopsy only","bool":false}]},{"id":219,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which one of the following is the surest method of identification?","answers":[{"option":"Blood group","bool":false},{"option":"Sex","bool":false},{"option":"Belongings","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Fingerprinting","bool":true}]},{"id":220,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"If a lady had a missed abortion, which of the following is the most suitable transfusion for her?","answers":[{"option":"Cryoprecipitate","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets and packed red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Only platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Packed red blood cells","bool":true}]},{"id":221,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 13-year-old female presents to the outpatient department (OPD) with on and off menorrhagia, bleeding gums, and petechial rashes. Her laboratory reports show the following results; Hb= 12.5 g/dl, platelet count= 350,000/mm3, activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT)= 49s (normal: 29-40s). Which of the following could be the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP)","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic microangiopathy","bool":false},{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":true}]},{"id":222,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 5-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department complaining of a painful and swollen knee. On examination, bleeding is seen within the knee joint but with no signs of physical trauma. His mother gives a family history of a maternal uncle who recently died of a bleeding disorder. Investigations show isolated increased APTT. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia A","bool":true},{"option":"Hemophilia C","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false}]},{"id":223,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"What is the inheritance pattern of glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Multifactorial","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":false}]},{"id":224,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A female patient is brought to the clinic after a snake bite with complaints of oozing blood from the wound site, widespread pinpoint and patchy red spots on her skin, and dyspnea. She appears lethargic, has cold skin, and is diaphoretic. She is immediately diagnosed with disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) secondary to envenomation by the snake. \r\n\r\nWhich of the following is the most appropriate step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oral antivenom","bool":false},{"option":"Packed red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous antivenom","bool":true}]},{"id":225,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 55-year-old patient is recovering from non-valvular atrial fibrillation. She is currently on warfarin and esmolol. Her most reason INR level = 7. \r\nWhat is the next best step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Add vitamin K antagonist","bool":false},{"option":"Stop warfarin","bool":true},{"option":"Add heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Add digoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Transfuse fresh frozen plasma","bool":false}]},{"id":226,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 50-year-old female presents to the clinic with complaints of hemoptysis and hematuria.  Upon further inquiry, the patient tells you that she was diagnosed with allergic rhinitis when she was 26 years old. Which of the following is the best diagnostic test?","answers":[{"option":"Serum antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies (ANCA)","bool":true},{"option":"Serum antinuclear antibody (ANA)","bool":false},{"option":"ESR and CRP","bool":false},{"option":"Serum anti glomerular basement membrane (anti-GBM) antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"IgM antibodies","bool":false}]},{"id":227,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 14-year-old boy presents to the clinic due to excessive bleeding from a wound. He tells you that he often gets bruises, especially on his knees and elbows. This patient most likely has a deficiency of factor VIII. What is the inheritance pattern of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Mitochondrial inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked dominant inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":true}]},{"id":228,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 71-year-old male presents to the clinic with complaints of unintentional weight loss, recurrent infections, lethargy, and night sweats. On examination, he has painless cervical and supraclavicular lymph node enlargements and the liver border can be palpated 1cm below the costal margin. \r\nLaboratory investigations show WBC = 15000 cells/mm3, lymphocytes = 8000 cells/mm3, Hb = 9 g/dL, blood smear shows a high percentage of small, mature lymphocytes, and the presence of smudge cells. \r\n\r\nWhat is the most likely diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL)","bool":true},{"option":"Burkitt's lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL)","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse large B cell lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hairy cell lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":229,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 29 year-old-patient, who is 15 days post-op after delivering a baby via c-section, presents to the clinic with complaints of localized swelling in her right lower limb. The swelling has increased in size over 2 days and is associated with pain and erythema. On examination, the swelling is warm to the touch and tender, and the circumference of the affected leg is 5 cm larger than the unaffected leg. \r\nWhich of the following is the preferred initial test in this patient for establishing diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"CT angiography of lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"CT venography of lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Serum D-dimer levels","bool":false},{"option":"CT angiography of chest","bool":false},{"option":"Doppler ultrasound scan of lower limb","bool":true}]},{"id":230,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A patient presents to the clinic with complaints of fatigue and exertional dyspnea. On examination, she has yellow discoloration of skin and sclera, subconjunctival pallor, and her spleen can be palpated 2cm below the costal margin. \r\nThe physician suspects intravascular hemolytic anemia and prescribes the relevant laboratory workup. \r\nWhich of the following findings does the physician not expect to see on laboratory reports?","answers":[{"option":"Elevated serum haptoglobin","bool":true},{"option":"Elevated corrected reticulocyte count","bool":false},{"option":"Increased urinary urobilinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated serum indirect (unconjugated) bilirubin","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated serum lactate dehydrogenase (LDH)","bool":false}]},{"id":231,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A young female presents to the clinic with complaints of exertional dyspnea, fatigue, and diarrhea. Stool examination shows the presence of proglottids. CBC shows Hb = 8 g/dL, MCV = 110, presence of hyper-segmented neutrophils and eosinophilia. The physician is suspecting a worm infection. \r\nWhich of the following species is this patient most likely infected by?","answers":[{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":true},{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloides stercoralis","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Toxocara canis","bool":false}]},{"id":232,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 40-year-old male presents with presents to the clinic with complaints of fever, vomiting, and fatigue for 5 days. On examination, there are petechiae and pallor. Laboratory reports show Hb = 9 g/dL, Platelets = 19,000/mm3, Cr = 6 mg/dL. \r\n\r\nWhat is the most likely cause of this patient's anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Macroangiopathic hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":false}]},{"id":233,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most correct statement regarding an allograft?","answers":[{"option":"An organ or tissue transplanted from one individual to another","bool":true},{"option":"A graft placed in a site different from that where the organ is normally located","bool":false},{"option":"A graft placed in its normal position","bool":false},{"option":"A graft performed between different species","bool":false},{"option":"A graft taken from the same individual","bool":false}]},{"id":234,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of action of alteplase?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits coagulation factor VIII","bool":false},{"option":"Causes vasodilation","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of glycoprotein IIb/IIIa","bool":false},{"option":"Activates tissue plasminogen to plasmin","bool":true},{"option":"Decreases cAMP","bool":false}]},{"id":235,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 45-year-old patient presents with a history of recurrent infections, easy bruising, and persistent fatigue. Further evaluation reveals anemia. What is the most likely cause of these symptoms in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Iron-deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":true}]},{"id":236,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2019","question":"A 12-year-old patient presents with a history of fatigue and yellowish discoloration of the sclera. On abdominal examination, splenomegaly is appreciated. An electrophoresis test is performed to evaluate the hemoglobin levels. What is the expected electrophoresis finding in a patient with beta-thalassemia major?","answers":[{"option":"Elevated hemoglobin C (HbC) levels","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased hemoglobin S (HbS) levels","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated hemoglobin A (HbA) levels","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated hemoglobin A2 (HbA2) levels","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated hemoglobin F (HbF) levels","bool":true}]}]
export default arr